Finding Aid for the Frederick Caldecott Slee Collection of Manuscript Scores, 1890-1954
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Original works and arrangements by Frederick Caldecott Slee, 1890-1954, I; Items 1-71
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Phantoms / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 51)
    Score consists of a photostatic copy for p. [1] and ink ms. for p. [2]. Song for voice and piano. Caption title. Author of text unknown. Includes one photostatic copy of this revised score.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Trio, piano, strings, A major Piano trio in A / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1939., 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 35 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 52)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Cover title. "Nov. 1939"--Cover. "6/39"--p. [4], score. Cello part contains a revision on a pasted insert.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Poet / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1949., 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Item 53)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Caption title. Text by Gustav Davidson. "Revised April 1949"--Cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Prelude and fugue, string quartet Prelude and fugue / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score (24 p.); 36 cm.+ 4 ms. parts; 33 cm. (Box 2, Item 54)
    Ms. (Ink) with emendations by composer in pencil and ink. Caption title. Violin and viola parts are marked with additions on insertions and all parts contain tacet markings.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Quartet, strings, C major Quartette in C / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score (41 [i.e. 37] p.); 35 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 32-34 cm. (Box 3, Item 55)
    Ms. (Ink) with emendations by composer in pencil and ink. Spine title. Score and parts contain revisions on pasted inserts. The parts and first two pages of the score are in one hand, the rest of the score is in another hand. "Revised Aug"--p. [1], score. Second movement excised from 2nd violin, viola, and violoncello parts. Second movement in score re-written to include additional vocal line with setting of text "Thy image pure and smiling," an English translation of the poem by J. Eichendorff, Dein bildness wunderselig; two pages of the movement within the score (p. 19-20) have been excised. Second movement later treated as a separate work by the composer, Music for tenor voice and strings.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Reminiscence: organ / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 2 ms. scores ([3] p.); 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 56)
    Cover title. Positive copy includes title, Adagio from Suite in F, on pasted insert.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Reminiscence; arr. Reminiscence / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 34 cm. + 1 ms. part (1 leaf); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 57)
    Holograph (Ink). Originally for organ; arr. for violin and piano. Caption title.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Romance, piano, violin, G major Romance in G: piano & violin / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1943., 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 34 cm. + 1 ms. part (1 leaf); 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 58)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Cover title. "May 1943"--Colophon. "First draft" [i.e. second draft]--Cover. Score and violin part contain revisions applied directly to manuscript and on pasted inserts. Score contains a performance instruction from composer in pencil on p. [2]: "Homer: To be played with left hand so right can turn".
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Romance, piano, violin, G major Romance in G: violin & piano / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1940., 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 34 cm. + 1 ms. part (1 leaf); 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 59)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Cover title. "Jan 1940"--Colophon. "Second draft" [i.e. first draft]--Cover. Score contains a revision on a pasted insert.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Romance, piano, violin, G major Romance in G: for violin and piano / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1946., 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 35 cm. + 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 60)
    Ms. (Ink). Cover title. "July 1946"--Cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Sarabande, string quartet Sarabande / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1943., 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 32 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 29-31 cm. (Box 3, Item 61)
    Ms. in ink with pencil emendations by the composer. For string quartet. Caption title. Score and parts contain numerous revisions applied directly to manuscript and on pasted inserts. Loose inserts in envelope. "Nov. 1943"--Colophon. "April 1941[,] Dec. 1943"--Viola part.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Sarabande, string quartet Sarabande / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1944., 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 33 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 29-31 cm. (Box 3, Item 62.)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. Caption title. Score and parts contain revisions applied directly to manuscript and on pasted inserts. "Feb. 1944"--Cover, score.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Scherzo, string quartet Scherzo / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([1] p. of music, [11] p.); 25 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 28-35 cm. (Box 3, Item 63)
    Holograph (Pencil). For string quartet. Caption title. Contains additional sketches on p. [1] verso. Viola part marked with a cut and a tacet marking.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 The sea / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 64)
    Holograph (Pencil). Song for voice and piano. Cover title. The poem, setting of Triolet, by Theodore Gianakoulis. Music based on Larghetto movement from C. Franck's String Quartet in D major. Newsprint copy of song text pasted in caption. Contains a revision on a pasted insert.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 The sea / Franck-Slee. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 65)
    Holograph (Ink). Song for voice and piano. Caption title. The poem, setting of Triolet, by Theodore Gianakoulis. Music based on Larghetto movement from C. Franck's String Quartet in D major. Two photostatic copies of score inserted.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Sun of the sleepless / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [betweeen 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 66)
    Holograph (Ink). Caption title. Text by Lord Byron. Cover contains words of song typewritten as text on a pasted insert. Scores contain a revision on a manuscript insert. Two photostatic copies of score inserted.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Variations on a hymn tune / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 37 cm. (Box 3, Item 67)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For solo viola. Caption title. Contains numerous revisions applied directly to manuscript and on pasted inserts. Contains additional sketches on front and back cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Variations on a hymn tune / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 68)
    Holograph in ink and pencil. For solo viola. Cover title. Score is marked with cuts and contains numerous revisions applied directly to manuscript and on pasted inserts.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Variations on a hymn tune Variations for viola solo on a hymn tune / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 3, Item 69)
    Holograph (Ink). Cover title. Contains minor revisions in ink.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 Variations on an old Dutch melody: (1626) / [Frederick Caldecott Slee]. 1943., 1 ms. score ([7] p.); 35 cm. + 4 ms. parts; 34 cm. (Box 3, Item 70)
    Ms. (Ink) with emendations by the composer in pencil and ink. For string quartet. Caption title. "Sept 1943"--Cover. "Adrianas Valerius Published in 1626, at Harlem. 'Nederlandtsche Gedenckclanck.' It is not known how many, if any, of the tunes he printed were composed by Valerius. At least some of them - there were nineteen in all - were folk tunes. The copies herewith are photographs from the original book furnished by the Library of Congress"--Inside cover, typewritten on pasted insert. Tune popularly known as: We gather together to ask the Lord's blessing. Score and parts contain revisions applied directly to manuscript and on pasted inserts. Includes a negative photostatic copy of Valerius' work as published in his Neder-Landtsche gedenck-clanck on a loose insert. Loose inserts in envelope. An alternative to the sixth variation in the composer's hand is included on a separate sheet of manuscript paper placed with the score; the verso contains an ink version of a viola part to another Slee work, Reminiscence. Typewritten English translation of text pasted inside back cover.
  - Slee, Frederick Caldecott, 1870-1954 [Untitled musical sketch / Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], [2] p. of ms. music; 25 cm. (Box 3, Item 71)
    Holograph (Ink). Title provided by cataloger. Sketches in piano format, intended instrumentation unknown.
- Transcriptions and recorder lesson, 1890-1954, II.; Items 72-77
  Arranged alphabetically by name of the original composer.
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006.Sonata, no. 3.Largo. Largo: de la 5'' sonate pour violin seul / J.S. Bach; trans. par Gaston Choisnel [and Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. part ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 72)
    First half of transcription (Choisnel): Holograph (Ink) with dynamic markings in pencil by Slee; Second half of transcription (Slee): Holograph (Pencil). Caption title. Transcription by Choisnel and Slee of the Largo movement from Johann Sebastian Bach's third sonata for solo violin, BWV 1005.
  - Fielitz, Alexander von, 1860-1930 Lieder, op. 26.Auf dunklen Wogen weil' ich allein Six songs by Alexander von Fielitz, op. 26: 6 "Auf dunklen Wogen weil 'ich allein" / [transcribed by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 3, Item 73)
    Holograph (Ink). Cover title. Includes English translation of text on cover.
  - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809 Trios, piano, strings, H. XV, 28, E major J. Haydn trio #4 / [music by Joseph Hadyn; transcribed by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. part ([7] p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 74)
    Holograph in pencil and ink. Caption title. Transcription by Slee of violin part from Haydn's piano trio, H. XV, 28. Contains various performance instructions and markings.
  - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809 Trios, piano, strings, H. XV, 24, D major J. Haydn trio #6 / [music by] J. Haydn; [transcribed by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. part ([4] p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 75)
    Holograph in pencil and ink. Caption title. Transcription by Slee of violin part from Haydn's piano trio, H. XV, 24. Contains various performance instructions and markings.
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 Trios, piano, strings, K. 502, B? major Mozart trio #2 / [music by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart; transcribed by Frederick Caldecott Slee]. [between 1890 and 1954], 1 ms. part ([9] p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Item 76)
    Holograph in pencil and ink. Caption title. Transcription by Slee of violin part from Mozart's piano trio, K. 502. Contains various performance instructions and markings.
  - Recorder lesson. [between 1890 and 1954], [3] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 3, Item 77)
    Ms. (Ink). Title provided by cataloger. Not in Slee's hand; included with his manuscript collection. Contains recorder care and performance instructions, a short list of recommended repertoire for the instrument, and six tunes for practice.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog:
Subjects
Music--Manuscripts
Genres
Manuscripts; Scores; Holographs
Associated Material
Additional Guides
All scores in the collection are cataloged in WorldCat and are available in BISON, the online catalog for the University at Buffalo Libraries, by performing a "Title begins with" search under "Frederick Caldecott Slee Collection of Manuscript Scores".
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Slee Family Collection, 1893-1981,
Mus. Arc. 12.2
Documents pertaining to the lives of Frederick Caldecott Slee and his wife, Alice, including music-related writings by Frederick Slee, correspondence, clippings about the Slees, documents concerning the Slee Bequest to the University of Buffalo, and concert programs. The collection contains eighteen photographs of friends and family. Includes a typewritten daily log of a sailing trip taken in 1914, by Frederick C. Slee and his friends, George T. Moseley and Louis Wright Simpson.